Guide to the National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians, Local 15 Records WAG.076
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians, Local 15 Records
1960-1990
1968-1985
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians. Local 15 (New York, N.Y.)
National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians
WAG.076
9.25 Linear Feet in 9 record cartons and one manuscript box
NABET, Local 15 was organized in 1965 by television and film production craft workers. The union's increasing work on feature films in the 1970s caused an explosion in the membership rolls. Competition that developed in the late 1980s between the International Association of Theatrical Stage Employees (IATSE) and NABET led to the revocation of Local 15's charter in 1990. The Local's membership voted to join IATSE, and were then admitted to various IATSE locals. The records include the Local 15 charter and by-laws, correspondence of officers, minutes of meetings and conferences, various subject files and photographs.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians, Local 15, in 1990. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 1990.009 and 1990.010.
Also donated by the National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians, 2001. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2001.042 and 2001.050.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
NABET Local 15 received its organizing charter in 1965, and the charter was reissued in 1968. In a union predominantly organized around the television industry, Local 15 was one of only three NABET locals devoted to film craftsmen. NABET Local 15 had its origins in the 1940s when the Association of Documentary Film Cameramen (ADFC) organized an independent union. In the late-1940s, the National Association of Broadcast Engineers (NABE), a Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO) member union, approached the ADFC and issued them a charter. At that time the name was changed to the Association of Documentary and Television Film Craftsmen (ADTFC) to accommodate the expanding craft categories covered under the NABE union umbrella. The ADTFC organized film crews working on low budget and television films. These were areas not organized by the International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees and Moving Picture Operators (IATSE), which was affiliated with the American Federation of Labor (AFL). In 1954, most of the 700 members of ADFTC joined the various IATSE locals. Those members who remained with the ADFTC formed a new union affiliated with the CIO's National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians (NABET). When the AFL and the CIO merged in 1955, IATSE and NABET remained separate entities.
With the increasing number of television commercials, series and feature productions in the early 1960s, workers previously unorganized by IATSE, were now organized by NABET, Local 15, known as the Association of Film Craftsmen. This new local, formed on September 19, 1965, would organize all the craft positions under one contract. The Local felt that this would be a more effective negotiating strategy for workers on low-budget productions. This policy encouraged Local 15's members to work in more than one craft in any area of production.
By the early 1970s, Local 15 expanded as its members increasingly worked on more feature films. Regional offices opened throughout the country, from Boston to Miami to San Francisco. In the late 1980s, NABET, Local 15 set up a meeting with officials of IATSE to discuss a possible merger. Soon after, the NABET international accused Local 15 of trying to secede. The international brought charges against Local 15, which subsequently went to court in an attempt to retain its member status as a NABET local. It lost the case, and the international revoked its charter in 1990. Local 15's membership voted to join IATSE, and was admitted to various locals of that union in October 1990.
Scope and Content Note
With the exception of a 1953 ADTFC rulebook, the records begin in 1966. They include minutes, by-laws, officers' files, members' correspondence, occupational safety and health concerns, scripts and legal files. Individual replies to a membership survey carried out in 1985 can be found grouped together at the end of the General Files, in Box 9. Taken as a whole, NABET Local 15's files shed light on the transformation of the film industry brought about by the introduction of video technology, and labor's response to that transformation.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically within each series. The files are grouped into five series:
Series I: Bylaws and Constitution, 1966-1988.
Series II: Minutes, 1965-1990.
Series III: Correspondence, 1970-1990.
Series IV: General Files, 1960-1990.
Series V: Photographs, 1969-1989.
Arranged alphabetically within each series.
The files are grouped into four series:
Missing Title
I, By-laws and Constitution
II, Minutes
III, Correspondence
IV, General Files
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians (NABET-CWA) Records (WAG 197)
National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians (NABET), Local 15 Oral History Collection (OH 032)
National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians (NABET) Printed Ephemera Collection (PE 024)
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Memorandums.; Surveys (documents).; Proceedings.; Transcripts.; Membership lists.; Ballots.; Correspondence.; Photographs.; Motion picture industry -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States; Constitutions.; Television broadcasting -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States; Minutes (administrative records); Contracts; Legal documents.; Agreements.; New York State Labor Relations Board; UA Columbia Cablevision; New Jersey Public Television; New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health; Daniels, Francis; Boehm, David; Miller, Richard; London, Marlene; International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employes, Moving Picture Technicians, Artists and Allied Crafts of the United States and Canada; Terry, David; Sherman, James P.; Wilson, Jim.; Association of Theatrical Artists and Craftspeople; International Federation of Unions of Audio Visual Workers; Mayor's Office of Motion Pictures and Television (NYC); National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians; United States. National Labor Relations Board; National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians. Local 15 (New York, N.Y.); National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians
- Series I: Bylaws and Constitution, 1966-1988.
  - By-laws, 1966-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - By-laws: Revisions and Approvals, 1966-1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Constitution, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Constitution: Amendments, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series II: Minutes, 1965-1990.
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Jan 1968-Dec 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Jan 1972-Jul 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Aug 1972-Oct 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Nov 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Dec 1972-Jan 1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Feb 1974-Jun 1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Aug 1974-Dec 1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Jan 1974-Mar 1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Apr 1974-Jun 1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Jul 1974-Sep 1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Oct 1974-Apr 1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, May 1975-Dec 1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Jan 1976-Aug 1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Sep 1976-Sep 1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Oct 1977-May 1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Jun 1978-Mar 1979 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Apr 1979-Jun 1980 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Aug 1980-Oct 1981 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Nov 1981-Jan 1983 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Feb 1983-Aug 1983 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Sep 1983-Feb 1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Mar 1984-Sep 1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Oct 1984-Feb 1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Mar 1985-Aug 1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Sep 1985-Feb 1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Mar 1986-Oct 1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Nov 1986-Jun 1987 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Jul 1987-Feb 1988 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Mar 1988-Dec 1988 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Feb 1989-May 1989 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Jun 1989-Jul 1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Aug 1989-Nov 1989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Dec 1989-Mar 1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, Apr 1990-Sep 1990 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Minutes: General Membership Meetings, 1965-1971 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Minutes: General Membership Meetings, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Minutes: General Membership Meetings, 1974-Jan 1979 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Minutes: General Membership Meetings, May 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Minutes: General Membership Meetings, Jan 1981-Jun 1982 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Minutes: General Membership Meetings, Jun 1983-Dec 1983, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Series III: Correspondence, 1970-1990.
  - Correspondence: Boehm, David, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Business Agents, 1978-1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Business Managers: A, 1972-1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Business Managers: A, 1979-1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Business Managers: B, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Business Managers: C, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Business Managers: D, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Business Managers: E-F, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Business Managers: G-H, 1978-1982 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Business Managers: I-J, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Business Managers: K-L, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Business Managers: M-N, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Business Managers: O-P, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Business Managers: Q-R, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Business Managers: S-T, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Business Managers: U-Z, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Daniels, Francis, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Executive Board, 1974-1980 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: Executive Board, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Executive Board, 1982-1985 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: Freeman, 1974, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: General, 1970-1990 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: Institute for Labor Relations at Cornell, 1978-1981 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: International President, 1978-1981 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: International Secretary, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: Inter-Union, Sep 1980-Dec 1986 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Inter-Union, 1987-1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Members, 1979-1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Members (GA), 1971-1980 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Miller, Richard, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Miller, Richard, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Miller, Richard, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Miller, Richard, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Miller, Richard, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Miller, Richard, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Other Unions, 1979-1982 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: President, 1972-1986 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Producers, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Regional Vice-President, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Secretary, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Secretary, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Secretary, 1977-1981 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Sherman, James P., 1979 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: Staff, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Staff, 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: Terry, David, 1978-1980, 1984-1987 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: Treasurer, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: Wilson, Jim, 1978-1982 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: Wilson, Jim (GA), 1978-1982 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Series IV: General Files, 1960-1990.
  - Agreements, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Agreements, 1980-1986 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU), 1979 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Arbitrations, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Arbitrations, 1981-1984 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Arbitrations, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Association of Theatrical Artists and Craftspeople (ATAC), 1981 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Automation House, 1979-1982 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Backstage: Anniversary Issue, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1970s-1980s (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Clippings: Screen Actors Guild (SAG), 1970s-1980s (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Committees: Constitution, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Committees: Contract, 1979-1984 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Committees: Finance, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Committees: Liaison, 1976-1978 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Committees: Low-budget/Independent, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Committees: Steering, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Committees: Video, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Contract Negotiations, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Contract Negotiations, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Contracts, 1980-1986 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Convention, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Departmental Tests, 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Departments, 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Departments: Camera, 1979-1982 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Departments: Editing, 1979-1982 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Departments: Electric, 1979-1982 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Departments: Grip, 1979-1982 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Departments: Make-up and Hair, 1979-1982 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Departments: Property, 1979-1982 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Departments: Script, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Departments: Set Construction, 1979-1982 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Departments: Sound, 1979-1982 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Departments: Staff Units, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Departments: Video, 1979-1982 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Departments: Wardrobe, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Economic Analyst, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Elections, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Elections Investigation Committee, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Executive Board: Joint Board Meeting with Local 52, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Executive Board: Retreat, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Fact-finding Hearing: NABET v. NABET, Local 15 (I), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Fact-finding Hearing: NABET v. NABET, Local 15 (II), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Fact-finding Hearing: NABET v. NABET, Local 15 (III), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Finances, 1975-1976, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Finances, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Finances: Audit, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - In These Times (film), 1982 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Insurance, 1981-1987 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees (IATSE): Clippings, 1980s (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - IATSE: Make-up and Hairstylists Local 798, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - IATSE: Trials, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - International Executive Council (IEC), 1975-1990 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - International Federation of Unions of Audio Visual Workers (FISTAV), 1978-1982 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Job Descriptions, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Job Reports, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Legal, 1971-1978 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Legal, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Legal (I), 1990 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Legal (II), 1990 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Letters of Agreement, 1979-1982 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Limited Budget Film: Questionnaire, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Lobbying, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - London, Marlene, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Mayors Office of Motion Pictures and Television (NYC), 1979-1981 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Membership, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Membership, 1979, 1985, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Membership Applications, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Members' Charges, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Members' Charges, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Members' Charges, 1977, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Members' Charges, 1984-1987 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Members' Charges, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Membership: Miami, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Merger, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Merger: Questionnaires (I), 1990 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Merger: Questionnaires (II), 1990 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Merger: Questionnaires (III), 1990 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Merger: Questionnaires (IV), 1990 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians (NABET) Local 11, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - NABET Local 16, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - NABET Local 331, 1978-1981 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - NABET Local 441, 1979-1981 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - NABET Local 531, 1979-1982 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - NABET Local 532, 1980-1982 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - NABET: Policies, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - National Labor Relations Board (NLRB), 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - NLRB Cases, 1974-1980 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - NLRB Cases, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - NLRB Cases, 1981-1985 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - NLRB Cases: Lee Rothberg Productions and directors Guild of America, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - New Jersey Public Television, 1978-1981 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - New York Committee on Occupational Safety and Health (NYCOSH), 1984-1985 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - New York State Labor Relations Board (NYSLRB), 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Newsletter, 1979-1985 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Officers Handbook, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Oral Histories: Green and Ross, Sep 18, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Oral Histories: Saburro. Pearl and Coyte, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Oral Histories: Sturm and Ross, Aug 25, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Organizing, 1979-1981 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Organizing: Pittsburgh Area, 1971-1977 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Organizing: WGBH (Boston), 1971-1977 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Political Action Committee, 1979-1982 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Political/Social Action Committee, 1978-1982 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Press Releases, 1983-1985 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Publicity, 1980-1990 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Questionnaires, Undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Roster, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Safety (I), 1979-1987 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Safety (II), 1979-1987 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Safety: COMPTU, 1980-1984 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Screen Actors Guild (SAG), 1979-1982 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Special Committee on the Future of NABET: Report, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Strike: Clippings, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Survey, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Turtle Heaven, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - UA Columbia Cablevision (UACC), 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Union Policies, 1975-1978 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Washington Section, 1979-1982 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Welfare Fund, 1975-1982 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Workers' Compensation, 1981-1985 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Surveys (completed membership survey forms), 1985 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Series V: Photographs, 1969-1989.
  - Contact Sheets, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Events, 1978-1989 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Labor Marches and Pickets, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Negatives, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - On Set Portraits, 1980-1988; undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - On Set Work, 1978-1983; undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Slides, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Oversize photographs, 1978, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 1-5)
- "Film and Tape Workers Unite!" banner, undated (Roll-storage Shared Tamiment 090)